import 'package:dzidzai_mobile/models/grammar/grammar_exercise.dart';

final List<GrammarExerciseModel> sentenceConstructionQuestions = [
    GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "i visited my grandparents in bulawayo and we spent the afternoon talking about their childhood",
    answer: "I visited my grandparents in Bulawayo, and we spent the afternoon talking about their childhood.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "The sentence should start with a capital letter, proper nouns like 'Bulawayo' should be capitalized, and there should be a comma before the conjunction 'and'."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "Although it was raining heavily the farmers in shiri village continued to work in the fields because the crops needed water",
    answer: "Although it was raining heavily, the farmers in Shiri Village continued to work in the fields because the crops needed water.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "A comma is needed after the introductory clause. Proper nouns like 'Shiri Village' should be capitalized."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The students studied hard for their exams but they also made sure to rest and relax on saturday",
    answer: "The students studied hard for their exams, but they also made sure to rest and relax on Saturday.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "A comma is needed before the conjunction 'but'. The day 'Saturday' should be capitalized."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "Did you light candles when the power went out.",
    answer: "Did you light candles when the power went out?",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "The sentence should end with a question mark, not a period."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "Yohwe, maiguru exclaimed after seeing how big the wound had gotten",
    answer: "'Yohwe!' Maiguru exclaimed after seeing how big the wound had gotten.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "An exclamation mark is needed after 'Yohwe!' and 'Maiguru' should be capitalized."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "our teacher explained the maths problem several times yet blessing still struggled to understand it.",
    answer: "Our teacher explained the maths problem several times, yet Blessing still struggled to understand it.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "The sentence should start with a capital letter. Proper nouns like 'Blessing' should be capitalized, and a comma is needed before 'yet'."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "wait for me, Takunda shouted, i am scared of the dogs",
    answer: "'Wait for me!' Takunda shouted. 'I am scared of the dogs.'",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "The sentence should start with a capital letter. Use quotation marks for dialogue and proper punctuation within the quotes."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "How come you want to join the debate club but you’re too nervous to speak in front of a crowd, Martha asked mary.",
    answer: "'How come you want to join the debate club, but you’re too nervous to speak in front of a crowd?' Martha asked Mary.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "The sentence should include quotation marks for dialogue, and 'Mary' should be capitalized. A comma is needed before the conjunction 'but'."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "we planned to go on a hike in the mountains but the weather in Mutare was too unpredictable",
    answer: "We planned to go on a hike in the mountains, but the weather in Mutare was too unpredictable.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "The sentence should start with a capital letter, and a comma is needed before the conjunction 'but'."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "While exploring the bustling markets of Harare which are known for their vibrant atmosphere and diverse range of goods including fresh fruits and vegetables handmade crafts and traditional clothing I couldn't help but notice the tantalising aromas of braai meat coming from the food stalls",
    answer: "While exploring the bustling markets of Harare, which are known for their vibrant atmosphere and diverse range of goods, including fresh fruits and vegetables, handmade crafts, and traditional clothing, I couldn't help but notice the tantalising aromas of braai meat coming from the food stalls.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence with the correct punctuation.",
    feedback: "The sentence should include commas to separate clauses and items in the list for clarity."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The bird made a nest in the tree of twigs and grass.",
    answer: "The bird made a nest in the tree that was made of twigs and grass.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should describe the tree more clearly by specifying what the tree is made of."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "I received a letter telling me that my grandmother was dead who lives in Masvingo.",
    answer: "I received a letter telling me that my grandmother, who lives in Masvingo, was dead.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "Place the adjectival clause 'who lives in Masvingo' immediately after 'grandmother' to specify which grandmother is being referred to."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The bellowing came from the bull in the corner of the kraal with the large horns.",
    answer: "The bellowing came from the bull with the large horns that was in the corner of the kraal.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should describe the bull more specifically by identifying which bull you mean."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The conductor asked the old man if he had a ticket who had boarded in Gweru.",
    answer: "The conductor asked the old man, who had boarded in Gweru, if he had a ticket.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should follow 'old man' to clarify which old man you are referring to."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The team scored the first goal in the green and white uniform.",
    answer: "The team in the green and white uniform scored the first goal.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should describe the team rather than the goal."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The woman wore a black dress whose husband had just died.",
    answer: "The woman, whose husband had just died, wore a black dress.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should follow 'woman' to specify which woman is being talked about."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The car crashed straight into the gate with faulty brakes.",
    answer: "The car with faulty brakes crashed straight into the gate.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should describe the car rather than the gate."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The passenger boarded late the plane who had misplaced his passport.",
    answer: "The passenger who had misplaced his passport boarded the plane late.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should describe the passenger and not the plane."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The old man was operated on by the doctor who had completely lost his sight.",
    answer: "The old man, who had completely lost his sight, was operated on by the doctor.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should describe the old man rather than the doctor."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The pretty girl was standing next to the car with a welcoming smile.",
    answer: "The pretty girl with a welcoming smile was standing next to the car.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence by correctly positioning the adjectival clause.",
    feedback: "The adjectival clause should describe the girl rather than the car."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "We travelled to Victoria Falls —---- enjoyed the breathtaking views.",
    answer: "We travelled to Victoria Falls and enjoyed the breathtaking views.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'and' to connect two related ideas: travelling and enjoying the views.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "He has never visited Harare, —------ has he been to Bulawayo.",
    answer: "He has never visited Harare, nor has he been to Bulawayo.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'nor' to connect two negative statements.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "You can have sadza with beef stew, —------ you can try the traditional dish of mopane worms.",
    answer: "You can have sadza with beef stew, or you can try the traditional dish of mopane worms.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'or' to present an alternative choice.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "We can go hiking in the Eastern Highlands, —-----we can explore the wildlife in Hwange National Park.",
    answer: "We can go hiking in the Eastern Highlands, or we can explore the wildlife in Hwange National Park.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'or' to offer an alternative option.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The musicians played mbira —------ marimba at the cultural festival.",
    answer: "The musicians played mbira and marimba at the cultural festival.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'and' to connect two items being played.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The football match was exciting, —----- the rains interrupted it.",
    answer: "The football match was exciting, but the rains interrupted it.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'but' to contrast two ideas: excitement and interruption.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The bus was delayed, —------ we decided to walk to the village.",
    answer: "The bus was delayed, so we decided to walk to the village.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'so' to show cause and effect: delay leading to walking.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The artists were talented, —------  their performances captivated the audience.",
    answer: "The artists were talented, and their performances captivated the audience.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'and' to add related information: talent and captivating performances.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The students stayed late at school, — — they had to prepare for the traditional dance competition.",
    answer: "The students stayed late at school, for they had to prepare for the traditional dance competition.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'for' to provide a reason or explanation.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The sun was setting, —----- the market was still bustling with activity.",
    answer: "The sun was setting, yet the market was still bustling with activity.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'yet' to contrast two events: sunset and bustling activity.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "She didn't want to go to the market, —----- did she want to stay home alone.",
    answer: "She didn't want to go to the market, nor did she want to stay home alone.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'nor' to connect two negative statements.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "She was tired, —---- she continued to work on her sculpture for the art exhibition.",
    answer: "She was tired, yet she continued to work on her sculpture for the art exhibition.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from the following options: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'yet' to show contrast between being tired and continuing to work.",
  ),
    GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "I wanted to buy fresh vegetables, —----- the vendors were closed for the holiday.",
    answer: "I wanted to buy fresh vegetables, but the vendors were closed for the holiday.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'but' to show a contrast between wanting to buy vegetables and the vendors being closed.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "We visited the Great Zimbabwe ruins, —------ they are a significant part of our heritage.",
    answer: "We visited the Great Zimbabwe ruins, for they are a significant part of our heritage.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'for' to provide a reason why you visited the Great Zimbabwe ruins.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "They heard about the charity concert,  —------ they bought tickets immediately.",
    answer: "They heard about the charity concert, so they bought tickets immediately.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'so' to indicate the result of hearing about the charity concert.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "Would you prefer to visit the National Gallery —----- the Museum of Human Sciences?",
    answer: "Would you prefer to visit the National Gallery or the Museum of Human Sciences?",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'or' to present a choice between two options.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "It was a hot day, —------- the children continued playing outside.",
    answer: "It was a hot day, yet the children continued playing outside.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct conjunction from: for, and, nor, but, or, yet, so.",
    feedback: "Use 'yet' to show contrast between the hot day and the children playing outside.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—---- it was a small village, it had a vibrant music scene.",
    answer: "Although it was a small village, it had a vibrant music scene.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Although' to show a contrast between the village size and its vibrant music scene.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—----- the concert started, the band members greeted their fans.",
    answer: "Before the concert started, the band members greeted their fans.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Before' to indicate the time when the band members greeted their fans.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—----- many people were sceptical, the new art gallery became very popular.",
    answer: "Even though many people were sceptical, the new art gallery became very popular.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Even though' to show contrast between skepticism and the popularity of the art gallery.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—----- the sun set over the Zambezi River, the landscape looked magical.",
    answer: "As the sun set over the Zambezi River, the landscape looked magical.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'As' to indicate the simultaneous occurrence of the sunset and the magical appearance of the landscape.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—----- the rains came, the fields were ready for planting maize.",
    answer: "Before the rains came, the fields were ready for planting maize.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Before' to show that the fields were ready prior to the rains coming.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—-----  if the weather is bad, the festival will continue as planned.",
    answer: "Even if the weather is bad, the festival will continue as planned.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Even if' to show that the festival's continuation is not dependent on the weather.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—---- you visit Victoria Falls, you will be amazed by its beauty.",
    answer: "Once you visit Victoria Falls, you will be amazed by its beauty.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Once' to indicate that visiting Victoria Falls will result in being amazed by its beauty.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The musicians played traditional songs —---- the early hours of the morning.",
    answer: "The musicians played traditional songs until the early hours of the morning.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'until' to show the duration of time the musicians played traditional songs.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "She practised her dance moves every day —--- she could perform perfectly at the cultural festival.",
    answer: "She practised her dance moves every day so that she could perform perfectly at the cultural festival.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'so that' to show the purpose of practising dance moves.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The government built new schools in rural areas —----- children could receive a better education.",
    answer: "The government built new schools in rural areas so that children could receive a better education.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'so that' to indicate the purpose of building new schools.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—------ the children played, the adults discussed community issues.",
    answer: "While the children played, the adults discussed community issues.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'While' to show that the children playing and adults discussing happened at the same time.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—------ the introduction of the new curriculum, students have shown significant improvement.",
    answer: "Since the introduction of the new curriculum, students have shown significant improvement.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Since' to indicate the time from when the introduction of the new curriculum led to improvement.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—----  the journey was long, the experience was worth it.",
    answer: "Although the journey was long, the experience was worth it.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Although' to show a contrast between the long journey and the worth of the experience.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "We are going to the concert —----- it rains or not.",
    answer: "We are going to the concert whether it rains or not.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'whether' to indicate that the concert attendance is regardless of the weather.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—-----  the roads were flooded, the villagers had to find another route to the market.",
    answer: "Because the roads were flooded, the villagers had to find another route to the market.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Because' to show the reason for finding another route.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "—-----  the performance began, the audience was completely captivated.",
    answer: "Once the performance began, the audience was completely captivated.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'Once' to indicate that the audience's captivation occurred after the performance started.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "You cannot enter the national park —------  you have a permit.",
    answer: "You cannot enter the national park unless you have a permit.",
    instructions: "Fill in the blank with the correct conjunction from: After, Although, As, Because, Before, Even if, Even though, if, once, until, since, so that, unless, whether, while.",
    feedback: "Use 'unless' to indicate the condition under which entry to the national park is permitted.",
  ),
    GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "The musicians, who ______ renowned for their unique fusion of traditional and modern Zimbabwean sounds, ______ performing at the Harare International Festival of the Arts last weekend.",
    answer: "The musicians, who were renowned for their unique fusion of traditional and modern Zimbabwean sounds, were performing at the Harare International Festival of the Arts last weekend.",
    feedback: "'Were' is the correct form for both instances, indicating past state and action.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "Do you know ______ the next concert, which promises to feature a variety of genres, is going to be held?",
    answer: "Do you know when the next concert, which promises to feature a variety of genres, is going to be held?",
    feedback: "'When' is used to ask about the time of an event.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "As fans of local music, ______ all excited to see our favourite band play live tomorrow at the newly renovated amphitheatre.",
    answer: "As fans of local music, we’re all excited to see our favourite band play live tomorrow at the newly renovated amphitheatre.",
    feedback: "'We’re' is a contraction of 'we are,' indicating current excitement.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "The artist explained that his inspiration came from a time ______ he visited the rural areas of Zimbabwe, ______ he experienced the rich cultural heritage firsthand.",
    answer: "The artist explained that his inspiration came from a time when he visited the rural areas of Zimbabwe, where he experienced the rich cultural heritage firsthand.",
    feedback: "'When' refers to the time of an event, and 'where' refers to the location.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "The venues, which ______ decorated with vibrant artwork and sculptures, ______ packed with fans eager to hear the latest hits from local musicians.",
    answer: "The venues, which were decorated with vibrant artwork and sculptures, were packed with fans eager to hear the latest hits from local musicians.",
    feedback: "'Were' is used for past actions and conditions.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "During the festival, many young artists showcased their talent in the open space ______ everyone, regardless of their background, could appreciate their work.",
    answer: "During the festival, many young artists showcased their talent in the open space where everyone, regardless of their background, could appreciate their work.",
    feedback: "'Where' refers to the location of an event or action.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "After the show, the performers asked the audience ______ they enjoyed the music and ______ they had any feedback to share.",
    answer: "After the show, the performers asked the audience if they enjoyed the music and if they had any feedback to share.",
    feedback: "'If' is used to introduce questions about conditions or possibilities.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "I remember the day ______ we first discovered that amazing street performer in Bulawayo, whose skills left us in awe.",
    answer: "I remember the day when we first discovered that amazing street performer in Bulawayo, whose skills left us in awe.",
    feedback: "'When' is used to refer to the time of an event.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "The workshops, which ______ organised to help budding musicians improve their skills, ______ highly praised by both attendees and instructors.",
    answer: "The workshops, which were organised to help budding musicians improve their skills, were highly praised by both attendees and instructors.",
    feedback: "'Were' is used to describe the past state and action.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    instructions: "Fill in the blanks with the correct word: 'where,' 'were,' 'we’re,' or 'when.'",
    question: "As art enthusiasts, ______ looking forward to the upcoming exhibition, which will feature traditional Zimbabwean art and music, showcasing the nation’s rich cultural diversity.",
    answer: "As art enthusiasts, we’re looking forward to the upcoming exhibition, which will feature traditional Zimbabwean art and music, showcasing the nation’s rich cultural diversity.",
    feedback: "'We’re' indicates that the art enthusiasts are excited about the future event.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'rewriteSentence',
    instructions: 'Join the sentences using the given conjunction.',
    question: 'Shona-speaking people live in Zimbabwe, Ndebele-speaking people live in Zimbabwe. (and)',
    answer: 'Shona-speaking people and Ndebele-speaking people live in Zimbabwe.',
    feedback: 'The conjunction "and" is used to join two ideas that are similar or connected.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'rewriteSentence',
    instructions: 'Join the sentences using the given conjunction.',
    question: 'Harare and Bulawayo are both in Zimbabwe. Bulawayo has a drier climate than Harare. (although)',
    answer: 'Although Harare and Bulawayo are both in Zimbabwe, Bulawayo has a drier climate than Harare.',
    feedback: 'The conjunction "although" is used to introduce a contrasting idea.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the new priest was not acquainted —----- all the people in his parish",
    answer: "The new priest was not acquainted with all the people in his parish.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'with' is used to indicate acquaintance or familiarity with people."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the committee squandered money —---- useless projects",
    answer: "The committee squandered money on useless projects.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'on' indicates the target or focus of spending."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "erica moyo is very good —--- maths",
    answer: "Erica Moyo is very good at Maths.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'at' is used to indicate proficiency in a subject."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the new driver was not familiar —----- the route",
    answer: "The new driver was not familiar with the route.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'with' indicates familiarity with something."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "takura prefers local music —---- foreign music",
    answer: "Takura prefers local music to foreign music.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'to' shows preference between two options."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "tuberculosis is characterised —------ a persistent cough and weight loss",
    answer: "Tuberculosis is characterised by a persistent cough and weight loss.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'by' describes a characteristic or feature."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "he lost his job —---- account of negligence",
    answer: "He lost his job on account of negligence.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'on' indicates the reason or cause."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the writer delved —----- fond memories of his childhood",
    answer: "The writer delved into fond memories of his childhood.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'into' shows immersion or deep involvement."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the children marvelled —--- the fire eater",
    answer: "The children marvelled at the fire eater.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'at' denotes marvel or attention towards something."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "smoking is often associated —---- lung cancer",
    answer: "Smoking is often associated with lung cancer.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'with' describes association with a condition."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "visitors should refrain —----- illicit activities",
    answer: "Visitors should refrain from illicit activities.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'from' indicates abstention or avoidance."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "my sister enrolled —----- the correspondence college last year",
    answer: "My sister enrolled in the correspondence college last year.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'in' is used for enrollment or participation in an institution."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "three members of the executive were expelled —---- the party",
    answer: "Three members of the executive were expelled from the party.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'from' indicates expulsion from a group or organization."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the visitors insisted —---- cooking their own meals",
    answer: "The visitors insisted on cooking their own meals.",
    instructions: "Complete the sentence with the correct preposition.",
    feedback: "The preposition 'on' describes insistence or demand regarding an activity."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "swimming is among those which are enjoyed by children",
    answer: "Swimming is among those activities that are enjoyed by children.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Specify 'activities' for clarity and use 'that' instead of 'which' for restrictive clauses."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "if one wants to do well, she must study hard",
    answer: "If one wants to do well, they must study hard.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Use 'they' to maintain gender neutrality."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "many girls falling pregnant is the result of a lack of sex education",
    answer: "The high number of girls falling pregnant is the result of a lack of sex education.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Clarify the subject by specifying 'The high number of' and adjust the verb to match."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the costs of medical care is getting more expensive",
    answer: "The cost of medical care is getting more expensive.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Change 'costs' to 'cost' to match the singular verb 'is'."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "vaccination is whereby people are immunised against certain diseases",
    answer: "Vaccination is the process by which people are immunised against certain diseases.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Use 'the process by which' for accurate description."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the tractor broke down, of which the farmer bought a new one",
    answer: "The tractor broke down, so the farmer bought a new one.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Replace 'of which' with 'so' for clarity in cause and effect."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "the residents discussed about the problem of theft",
    answer: "The residents discussed the problem of theft.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Remove 'about' after 'discussed' as it is unnecessary."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "some children wore uniforms, while some wore casual clothes",
    answer: "Some children wore uniforms, while others wore casual clothes.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Use 'others' instead of 'some' to avoid repetition."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "it was very hot that the child fainted",
    answer: "It was so hot that the child fainted.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Use 'so' to properly express the degree of heat."
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "if I was an eagle, I’d be king of all birds",
    answer: "If I were an eagle, I’d be king of all birds.",
    instructions: "Rewrite the sentence to correct any errors.",
    feedback: "Use 'were' for the subjunctive mood in hypothetical situations."
  ),
];

